<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tim Holzschuh</title><link>https://tholzschuh.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Tim Holzschuh</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://tholzschuh.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Galois Cohomology II</title><link>https://tholzschuh.github.io/math/teaching/summer23/galois-cohomology-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tholzschuh.github.io/math/teaching/summer23/galois-cohomology-2/</guid><description>During the summer term in 2023, together with Marius Leonhardt I&amp;rsquo;m creating the exercises and TAing the course Galois Cohomology II held by Dr. Alessandro Cobbe. The exercise sheets will be accessible through the relevant Mampf course on Thursdays, and will be discussed in the exercise session of the subsequent week:
When? Wednesday, 2:00 pm Where? SR6 Contact: tholzschuh@mathi.uni-heidelberg.de You won&amp;rsquo;t have to hand in written solutions to the exercises, but I strongly encourage you to spend a fair amount of time thinking about them in order to get the most out of the exercise sessions.</description></item><item><title>Using espanso to conveniently type unicode characters</title><link>https://tholzschuh.github.io/posts/espanso/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tholzschuh.github.io/posts/espanso/</guid><description>Peter Haine recently made me aware of the possibility of using a text expander to conveniently type unicode characters like Π, ⟶ and 𝒞 by typing things like :Pi:, :to: and :scC:.
After a quick search for available options, I decided to give espanso a try.
While the official package hub offers some packages with snippets relevant to mathematicians, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t really satisfied with any of the available options and instead started adding all the symbols I might need manually.</description></item><item><title>tikzcd snippets for VS Code</title><link>https://tholzschuh.github.io/posts/latex-snippets/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tholzschuh.github.io/posts/latex-snippets/</guid><description>For writing LaTeX documents, I use VS Code together with the latex-workshop extension.
One thing I particularly like about VS Code is its built-in support for snippets and how easy it is to implement your own.
As there aren&amp;rsquo;t any extensions in the marketplace providing snippets for commutative diagrams, I implemented some using tikz-cd on my own:
Demonstration This is what using the snippets looks like:
Result: I cycle through the preselected X, Y, S, T by pressing tab, which makes it very convenient to change the objects&amp;rsquo; names appearing in the diagram.</description></item><item><title>Galois Cohomology I</title><link>https://tholzschuh.github.io/math/teaching/winter22/galois-cohomology-1/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tholzschuh.github.io/math/teaching/winter22/galois-cohomology-1/</guid><description>During the winter term in 2022, I&amp;rsquo;m TAing the course Galois Cohomology I by Prof. Alexander Schmidt. The exercise sheets will be accessible through the relevant Mampf course on Wednesdays, and will be discussed in the exercise session of the subsequent week:
When? Wednesday, 2:00 pm Where? SR3 First session: 26.10. Contact: tholzschuh@mathi.uni-heidelberg.de You won&amp;rsquo;t have to hand in written solutions to the exercises, but I strongly encourage you to spend a fair amount of time thinking about them in order to get the most out of the exercise sessions.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://tholzschuh.github.io/maths/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 17:07:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://tholzschuh.github.io/maths/</guid><description>research papers Nonabelian basechange theorems &amp; étale homotopy theory 2023 arXiv with Peter Haine and Sebastian Wolf The fundamental fiber sequence in étale homotopy theory. 2022 IMRN &amp;nbsp; arXiv with Peter Haine and Sebastian Wolf teaching Galois Cohomology II Summer 2023 Exercise Sessions: Wednesdays, 2:00pm in SR6 of Mathematikon. Galois Cohomology I Winter 2022 Exercise Sessions: Wednesdays, 2:00pm in SR3 of the Mathematikon. The Grothendieck conjecture for affine curves Summer 2022 programme GAUS AG on Tamagawa's proof of the isomorphism conjecture for affine curves.</description></item><item><title>The Grothendieck conjecture for affine curves</title><link>https://tholzschuh.github.io/math/teaching/summer22/grothendieck-conjecture-affine-curves/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tholzschuh.github.io/math/teaching/summer22/grothendieck-conjecture-affine-curves/</guid><description>Together with Jakob Stix I&amp;rsquo;m organizing a GAUS-AG on Tamagawa&amp;rsquo;s seminal paper The Grothendieck conjecture for affine curves. A detailed programme can be found here.
When? Roughly every two weeks on Wednesday. Where? We&amp;rsquo;re rotating between Heidelberg and Frankfurt. Check out the programme for specific dates and places. Contact: tholzschuh[at]mathi.uni-heidelberg.de stix[at]math.uni-frankfurt.de</description></item><item><title>Galois and Fundamental Groups</title><link>https://tholzschuh.github.io/math/teaching/summer22/galois-and-fundamental-groups/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tholzschuh.github.io/math/teaching/summer22/galois-and-fundamental-groups/</guid><description>Together with Marius Leonhardt I&amp;rsquo;m supervising a seminar on Galois and fundamental groups. The announcement (in german) is here. If you&amp;rsquo;re interested, subscribe via MÜSLI or send us an email.
When? Thursdays, 02:15pm - 03:45pm Where? Mathematikon, SR 6 (Group A) and SR 7 (Group B) Contact: tholzschuh[at]mathi.uni-heidelberg.de mleonhardt[at]mathi.uni-heidelberg.de Handouts of all the talks can be found MaMpf.</description></item><item><title>Declarative and reproducible system and user management with NixOS</title><link>https://tholzschuh.github.io/posts/declarative-and-reproducible-system-and-user-management-with-nixos/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 18:15:26 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://tholzschuh.github.io/posts/declarative-and-reproducible-system-and-user-management-with-nixos/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been using NixOS as my main operating system for quite some time now.
As I recently upgraded my computer equipment by acquiring a new laptop, I decided that it&amp;rsquo;s time to invest some more time into further capitalizing on the features of NixOS. The main purpose of this post is to collect all the things I learned while doing so in a single place so that I&amp;rsquo;ll always be able to look it up again if need be.</description></item><item><title>Using LaTeX with Hakyll</title><link>https://tholzschuh.github.io/posts/using-latex-with-hakyll/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 18:13:04 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://tholzschuh.github.io/posts/using-latex-with-hakyll/</guid><description>Since Hakyll is tightly integrated with Pandoc, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to use LaTeX with Hakyll by enabling Pandoc&amp;rsquo;s LaTeX compile features. Most explanations I found online, like this one, seem to be quite outdated though and they don&amp;rsquo;t work verbatim.
The basic idea still is to set up a custom pandoc compiler using the
pandocCompilerWith :: ReaderOptions -&amp;gt; WriterOptions -&amp;gt; Compiler (Item String) function, but the internals used in the WriterOptions have changed.</description></item><item><title/><link>https://tholzschuh.github.io/other/gallery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tholzschuh.github.io/other/gallery/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Blüdhaven</title><link>https://tholzschuh.github.io/other/bludhaven/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tholzschuh.github.io/other/bludhaven/</guid><description>History Blüdhaven was a former whaling town, which was officially incorporated as a &amp;ldquo;Commonwealth&amp;rdquo; in 1912. The town had a generally poor socio-economic populace, owing in part to failed efforts to transform itself into a manufacturing and shipping center.</description></item><item><title>Hydra</title><link>https://tholzschuh.github.io/other/hydra/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tholzschuh.github.io/other/hydra/</guid><description>Motto Cut off one head and two will take their place</description></item><item><title>Tatooine</title><link>https://tholzschuh.github.io/other/tatooine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://tholzschuh.github.io/other/tatooine/</guid><description>A long time ago in a galaxy far, far away&amp;hellip;. A project was planned, but never completed</description></item></channel></rss>